<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-12-04T09:29:06-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hunting Stories</title><subtitle>A collection of adventures in the outdoors</subtitle><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><entry><title type="html">Camping So Far</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/other-stories/camping-so-far/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camping So Far" /><published>2025-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/other-stories/camping-so-far</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/other-stories/camping-so-far/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve taken the boys camping several times in the yard and have enjoyed it! I want to take them camping somewhere not so close to the house and also do it differently than we’ve been doing it. The way we’ve been doing it, we have done our normal dinner time and bed time routine except instead of putting the boys to bed, we just go out to sleep in the tent. I want to enjoy the part of camping that comes before just sleeping in the tent. I know there are still lots of things that I need to sort out and figure out such as food. The food thing is what intimidates me the most. I want to be able to keep the boys happy while also not making it too hard on myself. I know that that kind of knowledge only comes with time, experience, and a fair amount of research. I want to get the boys out camoing when it is cold or at least cool so that I am not so sweaty and uncomfortable. Looking forward to figuring this stuff out with my buddies!</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="other-stories" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking forward to figuring this stuff out with my buddies!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/camping-with-the-boys.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/camping-with-the-boys.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">First Deer of 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/first-deer-of-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Deer of 2025" /><published>2025-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/first-deer-of-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/first-deer-of-2025/"><![CDATA[<p>This deer season has been a bit unusual and great at the same time. I have taken both the boys hunting several times this year though we have yet to see any deer while out together. The whole corn situation has been different this year. I was really late getting corn put out both behind the house and at Nana’s Pasture. It took a long time for the deer to really get on the corn at the Pasture, maybe 2 weeks. The deer behind the house are not really coming to the corn anywhere close to daylight. I think this is because Jonah and Cole House are hunting more and are putting more corn out than other years and I think the deer are more comfortable where they are putting their corn.</p>

<p>I did go hunting once during bow season this year without the boys and saw a young buck come into range of the tree stand which I moved to the center of the pasture behind the house this year, that was pretty cool.</p>

<p>From the camera I saw the deer at Nana’s Pasture came to the corn right at daybreak on the 28th, so I made a plan to try to get one in the morning. On the 29th I got out to the spot under the Bradford Pear tree around 5:45. It was 25 degrees and clear skies. I’ve found that the best technique is to lay prone under the tree with the rifle on a stuffed backpack to decrease my profile. I didn’t see anything, so I left at 7. On the camera, the deer came out at 8:40 that morning so I was going to try again the next day and stay later.</p>

<p>The 30th I got out there at 5:30 and Nana’s 2 big dogs were barking at me until around 6. It was about 44 degrees and very cloudy with a light rain here and there. Four deer, two yearlings and two medium sized does, stepped out into the pasture at 7:30, but they were so close together that I couldn’t take a shot for fear of wounding another. So, I waited until the larger doe moved away from the rest a bit and took the shot at 7:41. She immediately went down on her chest and was running with her back legs into the brush. The impact was a bit more forward than I wanted, and both of her front legs were broken below the scapula. I could hear her crashing through the leaves. She stopped in the woods, but I could still hear some rustling, so I decided to wait 20 minutes before getting up to go look.</p>

<p>The other three deer were startled and confused. They stayed in the pasture for about 10-15 more minutes before walking into the woods to check on the doe.</p>

<p>I got up and started looking for sign around 8 and found no blood as is usual for me when I use a rifle. Maybe 50% of the time there is no blood until I find the animal, 30% there is a faint blood trail starting maybe 30-50 yards from where they are shot, and 20% of the time there is either a really good blood trail immediately or the deer just drops where it is.</p>

<p>I found the deer about 35 yards from where she was hit, 25 yards into the woods, and went back to the truck to pick up Kim and the boys so that they could help me look for the deer. They had a blast walking through the woods looking with us and they were so happy and proud of their dad. I dragged it to the truck, and we loaded up to go home. I had to get everything prepared to gut and process it as it was the first deer of the season. This took a little bit of time but, I got started gutting it using the hoist in the pasture behind the house at 9:45 and was done at 10:15. It was one of the more pleasant gut jobs I can remember, everything stayed mostly clean.</p>

<p>The boys came out to see me processing the deer, but it started to rain a bit Kim, Ella, Archer, and Chelsey went back inside. Theo stayed out for a while and was again joined by Archer as I was removing the hide.</p>

<p>Upon further inspection, the shot was low and forward, hitting both front leg bones just below the scapula. I was a little disappointed by this because I like to keep the bone in roasts from the front legs. The bullet hit both lungs and a fragment hit the heart. I got the hide off and removed the front shoulders. Then removed both backstraps, tenderloins, and the rear quarters. Archer stayed out for the whole thing and even helped me hang the meat in the schoolhouse. Theo came back out just as we were about to take the carcass down into the pasture. We finished just before noon.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="deer-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This deer season has been a bit unusual and great at the same time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-at-nanas-pasture.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-at-nanas-pasture.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Summer Ever</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/fishing/best-summer-ever/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Summer Ever" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/fishing/best-summer-ever</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/fishing/best-summer-ever/"><![CDATA[<p>This summer was the best one I’ve ever had in my life. Our daugher Ella was born, so I got to stay home on paternity leave. I was able to take the boys to the Chattahoochee river behind Langdale methodist in the canoe. They absolutely loved it. We had several spots that we always visited. “The Swimming Spot” close to the dam to the left where a little shoot of water made an island of coarse sand where the water wasnt too fast. “The Lunch Rock” where we would get out and eat lunch under the shade of a large tree that hung over the rocks. “The Muddy Spot” where the boys would get out and swim and play in the mud while I fished. We had a loop that we frequntly traveled and activities that we regularly did while on the water. The boys and I had a blast. We caught and ate a LOT of bluegills and other panfish as well as a faiir share of bass! The boys got to experience nature in an incredible atmosphere guided by me. They learned that we don’t always catch fish. We dont always have enough snacks. But no matter what the experience would be fun!</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="fishing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This summer was the best one I've ever had in my life]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/boys-in-canoe.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/boys-in-canoe.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Southern TNF</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/southern-tnf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Southern TNF" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/southern-tnf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/southern-tnf/"><![CDATA[<p>This morning, I decided I wanted to go a little more south in the National Forest as I had always hunted in the northern portion. I drove around making crow calls trying to get them to gobble but no luck. I was frustrated by several road closures that aren’t marked on the map anywhere. I stopped at a spot that looked good on the map, an area that had been burned pretty good in 2014 and had not grown up too much since. It was a road that had been closed to vehicle traffic. I parked the truck and walked half a mile up the closed road making calls here and there but got nothing. I decided I should head on to work as I’ve got lots of work to do and my time would be better spent doing that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="turkey-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wanted to go a little more south in the National Forest]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Deer Season Recap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/2024-deer-season-recap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Deer Season Recap" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/2024-deer-season-recap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/2024-deer-season-recap/"><![CDATA[<p>The 2024-25 deer season went well. I was able to get three deer put in the freezer, and it feels like I’ve got more meat than ever before. I didn’t get any shot oppotunities during bow season despite my efforts. I was able to take Theo three or four times and that was fun! He called it “Reindeer hunting”! The last deer I killed was the biggest I’ve ever gotten. I saw on my cellular camera that he was eating corn at Nana’s Pasture at around 3:30pm. Kim convinced me to go, so I hurried over there, parked by the road and snuck through the pasture keeping a clump of trees between us. He knew I was there and was looking at me when I took the shot at about 120 yards. He went 25 yards and tangled up in the brush at an old barbed wire fenceline. I also put Luke and John on a buck this year. It was Luke’s first deer! I helped them gut, skin, and butcher the meat and John has been telling me all the things they’ve made with it. I also gave them a Meateater cookbook to use. It was a good year and I had a lot of fun!</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="deer-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[He went 25 yards and tangled up in the brush]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/Ts-first-hunt.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/Ts-first-hunt.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Opening Day of Turkey Season 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/turkey-opener-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opening Day of Turkey Season 2025" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/turkey-opener-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/turkey-opener-2025/"><![CDATA[<p>Opening day of turkey season at Tuskegee National Forest. I got to the northern portion of TNF and found a guy at his truck in the spot I was going to hunt. I stopped and talked to him, and he said there was another guy up the road. I didn’t know that the road was blocked because a bridge was out further down. I told him I would look for a spot on down the road. The other guy wasn’t at his vehicle, and I had to turn around and go back past the first guy to get out of there. I stopped and asked him if he knew of any other places to go as I had no other backup plan. He said there was a spot at the northern edge of the National Forest that he’s heard turkeys at and that I should try there. I agreed and headed that way. I passed another truck that had just pulled up not far from the first guy. As I approached the spot at the edge of the National Forest there was a younger guy getting ready to hunt. I stopped and told him I’d go a mile or two down the road so I wouldn’t interfere with his hunt. I stopped at a good-looking spot with a nice big turn around and got ready. The morning was crisp and cool, just what you’d want for turkey hunting but no luck. I didn’t hear anything at that spot, so I did a 2-mile loop calling occasionally to try to illicit a response to no avail. I circled around and talked to Kim and the boys on the phone, got changed and headed to work.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="turkey-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The morning was crisp and cool, just what you’d want for turkey hunting.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunting-tuskeegee.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunting-tuskeegee.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Turkey Season Lamentations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/2022-turkey-season-lamentations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Turkey Season Lamentations" /><published>2022-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/2022-turkey-season-lamentations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/2022-turkey-season-lamentations/"><![CDATA[<p>This turkey season has been a huge letdown. I haven’t gotten to go as much as I’ve wanted to, but it’s still more than a lot of people get to, so I should be grateful. I really, really want to like turkey hunting, but it is so hard to like. I think my problem is that I just don’t have a large enough place to go hunting. Ideally, you’d go out looking for turkeys and if you don’t find them in one spot, you keep moving until you do. I am forced to just go to a spot and if they aren’t there, they aren’t there, I guess I need to find somewhere else I can go. Or just give it up. There’s only two weeks left in the season and I still haven’t heard a gobble. The weather has been perfect every time I’ve gone. Maybe the numbers are down, or the habitat just isn’t right for them anymore since it got clear cut.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="turkey-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This turkey season has been a huge letdown]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hopeful for Opportunities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/hopeful-for-opportunities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hopeful for Opportunities" /><published>2022-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/hopeful-for-opportunities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/hopeful-for-opportunities/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve only been out three times this season because I’ve been so busy with schoolwork, Theo, and the bathroom renovation. It’s already April 9th and all three times I’ve gone this season I haven’t heard or seen any turkeys. I’ve been to Nana’s and to Mr. Bud’s. I’m hoping I can get out more when I get done with the bathroom.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="turkey-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been so busy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Deer Season</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/deer-season/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deer Season" /><published>2022-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/deer-season</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/deer-hunts/deer-season/"><![CDATA[<p>I haven’t been keeping records of my hunts like I’ve wanted to. A lot has happened since last turkey season. This deer season I decided I wasn’t going to put out any corn. It was frustrating at times but all worth it in the end. My main strategy was “still hunting”. Creeping very slowly through the woods trying to spot deer before they spot me. I got several opportunities and I ended up getting two deer using this method. I came away with so much more knowledge about deer activity, and it was a lot of fun!</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="deer-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot has happened since last turkey season.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Gobble of 2021</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/first-gobble-of-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Gobble of 2021" /><published>2021-03-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/first-gobble-of-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hunting/turkey-hunts/first-gobble-of-2021/"><![CDATA[<p>I went to Nana’s Pasture early this morning and I didn’t even bother setting up the decoy. I called several times and got no response, so I headed straight back to the truck to go behind my parent’s house. I hurry out to the field next to the creek and try to get a shock gobble. I use an owl hoot. It works and a gobbler lights up across the creek maybe 250-300 yards away. I have an idea of where the bird might be, so I head for a “Y” in the trail. I set up a hen decoy in the bottom part of the “Y” and I sit in the “V” part of the “Y” facing the decoy. I start calling a little bit and he responds but he’s about 150-200 yards away in about the 5 o’clock direction. It’s not an ideal setup but I roll with it. He doesn’t respond to all of my calls. I think I only make him gobble four or five times and each time it sounded like he was getting further and further away. I did hear a hen over where I first started trying to get a shock gobble. I wait about 15 more minutes and then I start heading back to the truck. I am trying to get Noah Thompson to go hunting with me. I’m also trying to figure out how and where to go hunting in Tuskegee National Forest. I’m getting a little frustrated because my work and school schedule are not really conducive to going turkey hunting in the mornings.</p>]]></content><author><name>Joshua Etherton</name></author><category term="turkey-hunts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot has happened since last turkey season.]]></summary></entry></feed>